<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorial on SelinaDev</title>
    <link>https://selinadev.github.io/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorial on SelinaDev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 06:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://selinadev.github.io/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Yet Another Roguelike Tutorial, Part 4</title>
      <link>https://selinadev.github.io/08-rogueliketutorial-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selinadev.github.io/08-rogueliketutorial-04/</guid>
      <description>Part 4: Field of View Welcome back to the roguelike tutorial series. This tutorial will continue from where the last one left off. You can find the previous tutorial here: https://selinadev.github.io/07-rogueliketutorial-03/
Last time we created a dungeon to explore, but we also noticed that it&amp;rsquo;s not that exciting to explore if you know where all the rooms are from the beginning (also those rooms are empty, but we&amp;rsquo;ll handle that next time, one thing at a time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet Another Roguelike Tutorial, Part 5</title>
      <link>https://selinadev.github.io/09-rogueliketutorial-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selinadev.github.io/09-rogueliketutorial-05/</guid>
      <description>Part 5: Placing Enemies and Kicking Them (harmlessly) Welcome back to the roguelike tutorial series. This tutorial will continue from where the last one left off. You can find the previous tutorial here: https://selinadev.github.io/08-rogueliketutorial-04/
In this tutorial we will start spawning more entities. But first, we need a way to keep track of them. We already had an Entities node as child of Game. However, if you think about it, entities will be located within the game world, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet Another Roguelike Tutorial, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://selinadev.github.io/07-rogueliketutorial-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selinadev.github.io/07-rogueliketutorial-03/</guid>
      <description>Part 3: Generating a Dungeon This is the next part to https://selinadev.github.io/06-rogueliketutorial-02/. In this part we will handle dungeon generation. We will write a procedural dungeon generator that will give us a new dungeon each time. The algorithm we will use is relatively simple, we will place rooms in a way that they don&amp;rsquo;t overlap, then connect each room to the previous with an L-shaped tunnel. We can think about it like starting with solid stone and carving these structures out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet Another Roguelike Tutorial, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://selinadev.github.io/06-rogueliketutorial-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selinadev.github.io/06-rogueliketutorial-02/</guid>
      <description>Part 2: Generic Entity and the Map Continuing from the last tutorial ( https://selinadev.github.io/05-rogueliketutorial-01/ ), we will now move to creating a more generic entity, and then start on the structure of our map.
So let&amp;rsquo;s start with creating out entity class. I want to point out that my approach differs a bit from the original tutorial. In that tutorial all properties of an entity are set in its constructor. A later part eventually uses a factory pattern to create a few prototype entities in code and then spawn copies of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet Another Roguelike Tutorial, Parts 0 and 1</title>
      <link>https://selinadev.github.io/05-rogueliketutorial-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://selinadev.github.io/05-rogueliketutorial-01/</guid>
      <description>Here i&amp;rsquo;ll start an attempt for something I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do for a long time. I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in traditional roguelikes for a while now. Given that I&amp;rsquo;m also interested in game development, it should not come as a surprise that I have looked into how to make a roguelike as well. There is a very nice and reasonably comprehensive tutorial online, that exists in multiple versions. One of the more well known versions has to be the one at Roguelike Tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
